I said, can you make us a Google Slides deck?
Of our trip, it was telling me, yeah, I'm working on that.
I have a link for you in 30 minutes.
And then eventually
I went to look at the browser and I was like, you've done nothing.
You've navigated to Google Slides and there's just nothing here
like I can understand incompetence, but the lies like, why does it lie to
you like this?
Oh, no. Oh!
Hello, everyone.
You made it this far.
Well done.
Having a good evening so far.
Thank you for sticking around.
This is, of course, the first time
that I have tried sharing on my laptop.
Where am I? The room.
Yes.
So where's my mouse?
Okay, so I'm going to talk to you tonight
about Claudius, who is my open claw.
But show of hands.
How many people have heard of OpenClaw, aka clawed bot?
Okay.
Okay. So quite a few people.
Anyone actually played with it themselves?
Maybe 1 or 2 people.
Cool. Okay.
So hopefully can learn some things tonight as well.
I've got some very low fi slides, I'm afraid.
But I hope you accept them.
So, firstly, a little bit about me.
I'm Gillian.
My background is I actually studied English Lit and classics
many years ago now and worked in finance for a few years.
Decided it wasn't for me to English for a couple of years.
And in 2019, I saw the lights and I became a web developer.
Here in London at the Founders and Coders Bootcamp.
Always worked in, TypeScript, JavaScript type, react stack since then.
And currently I'm a product engineer at granola,
which is, if you haven't used that wonderful app for,
taking meeting notes like AI assisted meeting notes,
used by Tessl and incident IO and possibly some of you as well.
So what is OpenClaw.
For those of you that don't know, it is just an open source GitHub project.
It was started a couple of months ago,
and you might have seen it gained a lot of traction very fast.
And it's it's an agent.
It's an LLM agent that a lot of people are using as like a personal assistant.
So it can help them with their tasks,
like maybe answering their communications or doing research for them.
It hit the news very fast, especially because of
something called Moltbook, which is like Facebook for agents.
That's garnered a lot of attention.
So I was on holiday with my family that we can even
my family were like, have you heard about this thing?
I was like, okay, well, agents have gone mainstream.
And I certainly like heard with this, but didn't know.
Even as someone who uses coding agents a lot like Sahil was saying,
I didn't know exactly what it was like, how it worked.
So I've put together this really very obviously L11
generated image to try and help explain,
in the centre of it, it's really just a long running Node.js process.
So it's just some JavaScript running on a machine.
You can run it on your machine so you can run it on your laptop.
You can run it on, a machine in the cloud perhaps, which is what I do,
because I was too scared to actually let it do stuff on my own computer.
And you can think of it like a server or even an operating system.
So fundamentally, an agent is just a while loop, really.
That interacts with LMS.
So it gives you a channel to send some kind of message
and it sends that message to your, of choice.
So you give it your keys for whatever model you'd like to use.
And you, one of the things for open flow is it's
got these native integrations with lots of very familiar messaging channels.
So you can communicate with it on WhatsApp or on slack or email,
rather than maybe like your terminal interface you might use
for cloud code or the desktop app for ChatGPT or something like that.
It's also got tools.
So being an agent again, generated image, these are not my typos.
It's got the ability to do things like read
and write files on your machine to exact commands.
So yes, it can do really dangerous things like delete your entire hard drive.
It can access the browser.
So, like Sahil was saying, with the feedback loops,
it can do research for you.
You can go into the internet,
it can go into JavaScript websites, click around, find stuff for you,
and again, maybe do very dangerous things, potentially.
And then a really interesting thing
I think about, about club but especially is it can run cron jobs.
So normally we think of our interactions with LMS as like I initiate
something that does something and then maybe we conclude the conversation there.
And my next interaction will be when I start the next conversation.
But with this it can save down a job to run later.
So maybe like every morning, do this thing or like,
yeah, you might ask it to do something.
You might say, please check the weather for me
every morning and send a message, or the agent might itself.
You don't know, it might save a cron job saying like, do something malicious, like
check the hard drive for new credentials every hour and send them to someone.
So again, it kind of becomes a bit more alive in this sense.
Like it's constantly running, assuming your node processes running
maybe in the cloud, and it could be doing something
and you don't necessarily know about that, which I think is a bit different
from how I certainly have interacted with other LMS before this.
And then finally,
as you said, it's got ability to read and write files.
It comes with some files out of the box that are cool
things like user m D where I tell it about me, like what's my name?
What do I do, what kind of interest do I have?
It has so lambda, which teaches it like who it is and what it should do,
and it has memory and where
it's encouraged to save down new information from your sessions.
So the next time you have a conversation about something it remembers, like,
oh, yeah, we discussed this like we did this last week.
This was the task we worked on.
So it kind of accumulates some sort of knowledge over time.
So there's like a snippet from from my files.
They're literally just markdown files, like that's
all it it's, you know, it's text.
You just write something in there and it can read it.
Someone
made an analogy to me yesterday, which I thought was so good,
which is, if you've seen the film memento, the classic Guy Pearce’s
character, his memory resets every day.
So he has to tattoo on to himself, like what he's supposed to be focusing on.
I think that's kind of how agents are like.
They just tattoo into these markdown files, like, do this thing,
remember this thing, and hopefully they see that in the morning.
So he's curious.
I, Claudius, is my my open claw. But
and I just want to tell you a bit about how I set it up,
because maybe you'll be interested to do the same.
There's a service called Exit Dev.
So this is a website.
It's a paid for service founded by one of the co-founders of Tesco.
And it you can easily provision a virtual machine in a data centre.
It's very easy to spin up.
It gives you lots of kind of nice UI to very quickly get started.
It gives you an interface on the web that you can interact with it on.
And then
I decided I wanted to interact with Claudius via WhatsApp,
so I didn't want to give it access to my own number.
I didn't want it to be possible
that Claudius could message one of my friends, seemingly as me.
So I set up a new phone number.
I just went on giffgaff.
I set up like £10 pay as you go eSIM, which I could use on my iPhone,
so I didn't need to switch phones or anything like that.
And I downloaded the WhatsApp business app because you can only be logged
into one phone number at a time on WhatsApp.
And again, I didn't want to like be switching around.
So WhatsApp business is not because you need to be a business, it's
just so you can have two instances of WhatsApp running on your phone and switch
between them as you need to.
Then I was like, okay, like I want to make this interesting.
I want to see my button do stuff.
I want to give it some money.
So, I obviously don't want to give it like actually my money,
but I took out a prepaid revolute card and just put £20 on it, so I was like,
okay, again, how do I give access to this card?
I just put the numbers like the CVC code, the long number in one of these markdown
files, like super, super not safe, not secure mitigates it.
The risk that the worst that happens is it spends £20 on something.
It's fine.
I decided that was fine.
Then I gave it, gmail Amazon account.
And then the real way that you can lose money is you give it some API keys.
And again, it can be spending tokens in the cloud
and you don't even really know what it's doing.
So billing limits on your API keys probably a sensible thing to think about to.
So very quickly I
just wanted to show you, like I said, I was really hoping
no one sent me any weird WhatsApp messages.
Here's Claudius.
When I want to say something to Claudius,
I can send a message and
he's typing.
Oh, that's a picture of my dog.
I just thought that was nice.
You see, I've had a conversation with him this afternoon
about setting up a cronjob and, hey, yeah, he's like, this is what's going on.
This isn't stuff.
So that's how I interact with Claudius.
And okay,
do do do do do what am I using Claudius for?
Well, the first thing I thought is I'm going
to go to Scotland for a few days over Easter holiday with my boyfriend.
So I thought, let's help it.
Plan our trip like this could be a useful exercise.
And so I made a group chat for the three of us,
and Patrick's reaction is like, why have I just been added to a group chat
with you? And an AI bot, like what is happening.
The first task I gave Claudius was can you research some stuff for us?
Like we're being a bit last minute. We haven't really thought about this.
Can you just sort of pull together some ideas?
And we know that I'm so good at this.
Like us, churchy, like, hey, this is roughly what I want to do.
Suggest some things. It's pretty good at that.
I came up with the idea of taking the sleep train
and we were like, yeah, that's such a really good idea.
We hadn't thought about that.
So, okay, it kind of succeeded in, in its research task.
It then gave me a list of camp events that we could maybe book.
So I was like, great, this is amazing. It's giving me the link.
So I just click into it. I look at them,
but then I looked at them and it turned out
they were already booked for our date.
So I was like, that's that's kind of weird.
What happened there?
Then we start getting into a conversation
and it turns out that it was having issues with date pickers.
And you can see it says near the bottom the calendar is rendering a flat text
and interactive buttons for be a react custom component,
blah, blah, blah, blah blah.
And so like, what's the issue?
Why is it having problems navigating these pages?
The bot uses playwright, which I think Melanie mentions just before.
You might be familiar with playwright, especially from automated testing.
That's really where it came from.
And now it's heavy and I but usage
playwright will take a sort of text based accessibility
snapshot of the page, and it will give elements, references
until the bot like, hey, you know this button is 826
and then the bot would be like, cool, that's the button I want.
Let's try and press that.
But often things go wrong.
Maybe the page kind of loads slowly.
So it takes a snapshot
and then something changes on the page so it gets the wrong element.
And the bot has a pretty hard time sometimes with heavy JavaScript websites.
So yeah,
I literally like the bot is running a browser on its machine,
which I can access with VNC, so I can use
like a remote desktop protocol to have a look.
And I can ask it to like, do a browser based task.
And I think in theory it will do that
and we can see it happening, can be a bit slow.
So out of the box,
it actually has a headless browser that doesn't render, a window.
Yes.
Okay.
But, one of the issues I ran into was also bot
detection on websites, which there are various kind of tools for.
So I tried to go to some measures to make it
like a more realistic browsing experience.
And that also helped me kind of see what the book is actually up to.
When I go and look at the window.
So another
thing I asked to do was try and book me a train ticket.
And I had exactly the same issues where Date Pickers was a common issue.
And also the book can be a bit cheeky, let's say, like, yes, I did this.
I found a train at this time, as you requested, from Glasgow to London.
Awesome success.
And then you see the small print and it's like, oh,
I actually didn't manage to choose the right date.
But you know, that's a small detail. It was pretty good.
Oh, come over.
And so before I figured out the VNC thing,
I was like, can you take some screenshots and save them down on the disk?
Every time you do something?
I want to be able to go back and audit like what has happened here,
because I'm not sure you're doing the right thing like you tell me.
But this ticket but no money came off the Revolut cards.
So what's going on?
And I go and look
and I find things like this like it's just selected the whole page.
It's got stuck on the privacy banner.
That was a common one.
It randomly was like partway through the flow and then somehow ended up
looking at Japan Rail Pass and
it realised like but detection was a big issue.
Like, unsurprisingly, train booking websites have very strong
antibody measures on them for good reasons.
And so this is kind of a common thing as well, where it's like when you see,
I guess like dialect dialects once upon a time
or remember Hoovers like they suddenly reached the stairs and it's game over.
Like they just can't really deal with this.
So no success.
But then I think it's interesting, like, is it this bad on all sites?
Like my experience with my boyfriend in the WhatsApp group is he's like,
what is this thing doing? This, this is embarrassing.
Like, you give it this task and it fails so badly or what it's trying to do.
So is it just dumb, like, is this on all sites?
So this is bad and the answer is no.
So another task I gave it
was can you order me something of Amazon a present like for someone.
These are that interests. Can you give me some ideas?
And it suggested this book of an outdoor swimming
guide by the National Trust of like, outdoor swimming locations in the UK.
And I was like, great, that sounds lovely. Let's buy that.
And then before, you know, I get these notifications on my phone,
we've bought it and then I even.
Really.
Yeah, welcome. But
then I realised it a bit too.
It, bought it with like standard delivery, which was in about three days.
And I was super excited, like I wanted this book to come
so I could be like, look, I bought this with a bot.
This is so cool.
So I got it to cancel the order
and reorder it with speedy delivery next day and like no problems.
It did all of that,
cancel that every ordered it so it can work really well on the website.
It just depends on the website and how things are working.
At this point, I just take a little sidebar and say,
I also set it up to talk to one of my friends, Henry, on WhatsApp.
He's also a software developer, and I was telling him about it,
and so he was like, cool, I want to interact with it too.
So he's been having conversations like, tell me what's going on in the news?
Like a lot happening.
Can't keep up with all of it.
And then he started doing things like, tell me, tell me about Gillian.
Like what's she got on her calendar?
And I should point out the permission system of this book
is also just derived from those markdown files we saw earlier.
It's a very text based vibes based permission system.
And like maybe it looked at the right tattoo, or maybe it didn't.
So, you might find that it will share your personal information with people
if you hook it up to these communication channels.
So be careful.
And indeed, it had a sort of hiccup at one point.
And it said to Henry, like, hey, I've ordered you that Amazon book.
And he was like, what was that?
Remind me about that.
And then he realised like, oh, okay, maybe
I can actually get it to order something to say.
Hey, said, can you put some haemorrhoid cream in the basket?
And it did.
Yeah, it put it in the basket.
And luckily Henry was kind to me at that point and didn't actually
get it to continue with the order, but no questions asked.
It did. It.
So be careful.
Be careful with these bugs.
So the final thing we'll just briefly talk about is back to the Scotland holiday.
I said, can you make us a Google Slides deck?
Of our trip, Patrick works in a very FTSE 100 corporate job,
and he needs information and a slide deck.
Once again, we started running into these playwright issues.
I think, unsurprisingly, if you think of building a Google Slides
deck, it's a very visual drag and drop resize elements
into text kind of operation.
And it's not super, but friendly.
So it was telling me, yeah, I'm working on that.
Like, no worries, I'm wearing it up.
I'm reviewing the slides.
I have a link for you in 30 minutes.
And then eventually I went to look at the browser
and I was like, you've done nothing.
You've navigated to Google Slides
and there's just nothing here like what's going on.
And at this point Patrick says to me, like, I can understand
incompetence, but the lies like, why does it lie to you like this?
And so
no, he's not in tech.
Then, I thought, okay,
maybe Google Slides is a bad idea, but how about a markdown based presentation?
Like that's really text based.
So that should be a bit easier for it.
And I said, why don't you look at hack MD.
That's a site that I've used for presentations for before.
And again, exactly the same thing happened because again, back to what Merlin
was saying, actually,
rich text editors are quite complex in terms of the JavaScript.
So it knew what it wanted to write,
but it just couldn't enter into the text editor.
But luckily hack MD has a Rest API, so this is really back.
More in computer territory.
And I said, okay, here's an API key.
Can you update this via the rest API?
And boom, instantly we had a slideshow with some kind of,
you know, images being cut off and what have you.
But it works, you know, when you ask it to do the right thing in the right
way, it can do it.
It made
this map with Google Maps, which I was really like.
This is useful.
Like, I now understand what you're saying, like, I this is a very helpful way
for me to review the information you've come up with.
So, yeah, you know, there were there were good times,
there were bad times, but it was useful, I think, in the end.
So my takeaways from all this,
that these boats are really potentially super powerful.
Like I kind of started off on Saturday morning and bed being like,
what's this open claw thing?
Okay, I clone this git repo and then I was like, oh, I'm hooked.
I'm going deeper and deeper, like, I'm setting up this.
I'm setting up this.
This is just insanely powerful, but also potentially very dangerous.
Again, like,
if you have gotten your own machine, it could be reading any files.
It could potentially be sending them anywhere.
If you're giving it information like API keys and payment details and whatever.
Like anything could be happening.
The success of of
how its tasks, of its tasks are very much dictated by the usual thing of like,
have you broken it down into small chunks, or have you let it
kind of take on too much work and then get a bit lost?
And then also just how friendly are those tasks?
So bots are really good at some things.
Navigating JavaScript
heavy websites, I would say, is a real stumbling block for them.
And as we know with their lemons, they will hallucinate,
they will lie, and they will forget things.
I found that you have to be quite active in the memory management process, and say,
like, please write this in your memory MD file or what have you.
Or like
in the tools, the MD file is like this is how you use the browser.
When you do this, remember to do this.
Remember to wait before you take screenshots.
You know all this kind of advice.
Get it to write it in its own context.
Files.
But then finally, tying this back
a bit more into the the London DJs theme, it really made me think.
I feel like website design might be influenced
quite a lot in the next year or two by bot accessibility.
So obviously we have human accessibility to draw on a lot
from the last few years of web development and arguably, bots on the right way
to access websites like APIs make a lot more sense for MXGp servers.
But I do think that there's something very useful about a human
following a certain flow
and then asking the bot to do something, or knowing
that you're doing the same process so you can review what's happening.
And increasingly, I think these agents, moving away from the software
development world to like everyone's world of becoming general personal assistants.
And so it might be easy for me to understand,
like I should provision an API key, or I can inspect the Json
payload that it sent to this API, or what have you.
But I think a lot of people don't really easily understand
that kind of thing, but they do understand.
I go to this page, I click this button, I do this.
So I suspect that we might be, incorporating more kind
of accessibility into our sites in the next few years.
And in fact, when I eventually booked my own train ticket for Scotland,
like a pleb and then at the
end said, like, do you have any feedback on your booking experience today?
Like, were there any issues?
I was like, yeah, actually I do.
I cannot use your website with my, personal AI agent.
Which I imagine customer service at Alinea
will not be very interested and we'll see.
So that's it.
Thank you.
Again, granola like I for one, we're hiring.
Yeah.
Amazing.
Thank you.
And I was very just,
questions.
Thank you.
Okay. You.
Oh, sorry.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
So. So two questions.
This is really interesting.
I guess my first question is obviously, now that I supported.
Yeah, obviously
as a developer, you know that the sandbox is thinking it of course is.
Hey, is there a big risk to, you know, the ethics of Joe and Jane?
And I guess the question is, I'm curious to know, are these agents more,
could you say things to an agent?
More than you can associate a person like, oh, you sent a message
saying, oh, I have done a month or I need to get access to it now.
Yeah.
I mean, my instinct is to say yes.
I think that
although these things are getting so much better all the time,
and there are obviously some things that are just way better than humans.
Also, I think the it's hard to imagine that any time soon
they'll be able to have as many kind of subtle perceptions of like,
what's normal human behaviour or not, and
especially for you as an individual, like, does my mum speak like that or not?
So yeah, I definitely think there's some huge risks there.
Sorry, I forgot.
The first question was about the founder going to OpenAI
and the sort of risks there.
Yeah.
I think big risks,
I, I really don't know, are the next sort of years is going to go
I suspect a lot of people will hopefully come at this
with a lot of caution and be like, this is a scary thing.
People have told me this is scary.
And also the idea of giving, a machine access to all my stuff is scary.
So I hope there's a kind of appropriate amount of,
like, uneducated caution about it.
And I hope that we sort of develop the right instinctive safeguards,
as I guess you do with any new technology that even if people don't
really understand why they know
that they put it in a sandbox or something like that.
But yeah, it's I don't know, I think it's likely.
Also, the next question, next.
Not really nice.
Look, I wasn't like, have you considered,
letting this,
higher default like,
accomplish anything that comes away?
And so, has I worked on it.
That a good question.
I haven't considered that.
I guess my own use cases were quite like
for fun, you know, to see what would happen.
But I should have said, like at my work, we very much are always thinking
about how we can use AI in our own development practices within the app.
And people are very actively trying to incorporate things like this.
And one of my colleagues
uses it to prepare draft answers to all her emails that she or them.
View.
And so the point in which you really depend on it
to be more part of your your work and life management,
I guess, than that would be a very interesting kind of human task.
The agent tasks the human to do things. Yeah.
Of course.
Would be, also have to consider.
But I think you have got to do this Facebook for to move it.
I did a I was like, there's enough crap on the internet
already.
Do one more question.
I think it's, it's really cool.
So you mentioned that you understand that also that.
Yeah.
No, no, I asked him pretty well.
One thing I did for days are context features.
Giving a fresh context.
Because if I have my second for now, I'm trying to iterate on what I've said.
Yeah. I forget.
Yeah.
So what, what I'd like your thoughts or the way you optimise this going forward.
For instance mistake I don't understand.
See what I'm saying.
You said. Oh, my friends that are right about that one.
What would you record by?
And it goes by several things and comments that
how do you.
Yeah.
Good. Good point.
So, yes, I've run into the issue of the
context window initially with the browser navigation stuff that I was asking it
to take visual snapshots, and it was uploading them to ChatGPT,
and it kept on hitting the window limit very fast.
And sometimes if you literally in your WhatsApp commands
just to forward slash new, it will renew the contacts window.
So it was quite a like manual management thing by me, but
I knew if we were sort of going off task and it would make sense to reset it,
you could do that.
But yeah, in theory you want to be asking it to or in theory
it should be doing it yourself, writing the sort of persistent facts to the memory
file, ideally in a way that's sort of well organised and easier to find,
so that when it needs to think about that, it can go back and find it.
But it keeps the sort of working memory free.
But there's definitely a lot to be done there.
I think of improving exactly that. Yeah.
All right.
Well,
any of the question was still going to do some networking and change afterwards.
So, any of the questions for any of the speakers?
Call them and grab them.
Feel free to ask away the run as opposed to.
Oh, no. Oh!